<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>The Concurnas Programming Language</title>
  <link>https://concurnas.com</link>
  <description>Concurnas is an open source JVM programming language designed for building reliable, scalable, high performance concurrent, distributed and parallel systems</description>
  
<item><title>JAXLondon - Concurnas - a Modern JVM Language for Modern Software</title><link>https://concurnas.com/video/index.html</link><description>JAXLondon - Concurnas - a Modern JVM Language for Modern Software <a href="https://concurnas.com/video/index.html"> Watch it here...</a><p>In recent years, software engineering and the role of software engineers has changed. Teams have evolved heterogeneously to incorporate technical, non-technical and domain specific experts. Solutions are now expected to be rapidly delivered, whilst also being highly performant and scalable. At the same time we have the cloud and ever more increasingly powerful multi-core CPU and GPU hardware at our disposal. Programming languages are the principle tools by which we interact with our machines to solve problems. The world needs our languages to evolve in order to suit this new environment.</p><p>In this talk we explore Concurnas, a JVM language designed for solving the concurrent, distributed and parallel programming problems faced by the modern enterprise. We see how Concurnas affords developers of all ability the capacity to easily leverage modern multi-core CPU and GPU hardware for solving problems. We learn how Concurnas's unique simplified model of concurrent and GPU computing allows developers to easily create not only new code, but use leverage their existing Java (or JVM language) code to build safe, reliable, concurrent software.</p></description></item>
<item><title>jokerconf - Back from the 70s - the Concurnas concurrency model!</title><link>https://concurnas.com/video/index.html</link><description>jokerconf - the Concurnas concurrency model! <a href="https://concurnas.com/video/index.html"> Watch it here...</a><p>Concurnas is a JVM programming language designed for concurrent and parallel computing. It provides an alternative concurrency model to that of threads and locks found in Java. Much of the work which inspired this concurrency model was conducted in the 1970's but largely forgotten due to chip architectures being single cored in nature.</p><p>But things changed recently, now multi-core CPUs are commonplace and developers are obliged to implement systems utilizing concurrency in order to obtain optimal performance. Furthermore, we have also recently seen GPUs take center stage for powering general-purpose parallel computing, developers have yet another tool at their disposal for solving computational problems.</p><p>In this session, a high-level overview of Concurnas, focusing on concurrency and GPU programming will first be provided. Then we shall deep dive into the inspiration for and implementation of the Concurnas concurrency model within the language, compiler, and runtime. Finally, we'll explore how GPU computing is implemented within Concurnas and how this integrates with the core concurrency model.</p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas at jokerconf this year</title><link>https://jokerconf.com/en/2020/talks/5adlth7fgf7gkwl6p17fc4/</link><description><p>We're presenting Concurnas at <a href="https://jokerconf.com/en/2020/talks/5adlth7fgf7gkwl6p17fc4/">jokerconf</a> this year</p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurrent programming with Concurnas</title><link>https://blogs.oracle.com/javamagazine/concurrent-programming-with-concurnas</link><description><p>Concurrent programming with Concurnas in <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/javamagazine/concurrent-programming-with-concurnas">Oracle Java magazine</a>.</p></description></item>
<item><title>The Concurnas Programming Language online talk</title><link>https://concurnas.com/video/index.html</link><description>The Concurnas Programming Language - Thalesians online talk. <a href="https://concurnas.com/video/index.html"> Watch it here...</a><p>We have at our disposal never before seen compute capability. CPU's are now multi-core, general purpose GPU computing has gone mainstream and compute is available on tap via the cloud. But leveraging this power with existing languages is a challenge. This comes at a time when the modern enterprise requires results to be delivered at an ever increasing pace. Languages like Python have grown in popularity due to their simplicity and focus on rapid results, but performance is lacking, conversely languages such as C++ and JVM languages like Java present excellent performance but are hard to master. We need a solution to these problems.</p><p>In this talk we explore Concurnas, a JVM language created for leveraging the power of modern CPU and GPU hardware. Concurnas is specifically designed for solving the concurrent, distributed and parallel programming problems faced by the modern enterprise. We learn how Concurnas's unique simplified model of concurrent and GPU computing allows results to be rapidly delivered in a performant, scalable manner whilst allowing existing Java (or JVM language) code to be leveraged.</p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas Q+A on InfoQ</title><link>https://www.infoq.com/news/2020/05/concurnas-jvm-gpu/</link><description><p>A new Q+A article about Concurnas at <a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2020/05/concurnas-jvm-gpu/">InfoQ</a>.</p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas @ JAX London 2020</title><link>https://jaxlondon.com/java-core-jvm-languages/concurnas-a-modern-jvm-language-for-modern-software/</link><description><p>We have been invited to speak about Concurnas at <a href="https://jaxlondon.com/">JAX LONDON 2020</a>. Join us to see our talk: <a href="https://jaxlondon.com/java-core-jvm-languages/concurnas-a-modern-jvm-language-for-modern-software/">Concurnas - a Modern JVM Language for Modern Software</a></p></description></item>
<item><title>March 2020 Newsletter</title><link>https://concurnas.com/newsletters/march2020.html</link><description><p>The March 2020 newsletter covers the latest release, Concurnas in the press, the growth of Concurnas and how volunteers can contribute to the language, <a href="https://concurnas.com/newsletters/march2020.html">check it out!</a></p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas 1.14.020 released</title><link>https://concurnas.com/download.html</link><description>Download the <a href="https://concurnas.com/download.html">latest version of Concurnas</a>. Checkout the <a href="https://github.com/Concurnas/Concurnas/releases/tag/1.14.020">release notes here.</a></description></item>
<item><title>Jaxenter tutorial on Concurnas</title><link>https://jaxenter.com/introducing-new-jvm-lanaguage-concurnas-167915.html</link><description><p>A new tutorial introducing the basic syntax, concurrency model, object orientation, dependency injection, DSL and GPU computing functionality of Concurnas available at <a href="https://jaxenter.com/introducing-new-jvm-lanaguage-concurnas-167915.html">Jaxenter</a>.</p></description></item>
<item><title>Java vs Concurnas</title><link>https://concurnas.com/learnmore/concVsJava1.html</link><description><p>A new three part article highlighting the <a href="https://concurnas.com/learnmore/concVsJava1.html">differences between Java and Concurnas</a> and why Concurnas is recommended for modern software development on the JVM</p></description></item>
<item><title>waterstechnology interview</title><link>https://www.waterstechnology.com/operations/4856196/ex-jp-morgan-trader-tackles-complex-computing-with-new-programming-language</link><description><p>A new interview with the Founder of Concurnas on <a href="https://www.waterstechnology.com/operations/4856196/ex-jp-morgan-trader-tackles-complex-computing-with-new-programming-language">waterstechnology</a> - [Paywall]</p></description></item>
<item><title>programmez.com Concurnas article [French]</title><link>https://www.programmez.com/actualites/concurnas-un-langage-pour-la-jvm-dedie-la-programmation-parallele-et-distribuee-30276</link><description><p>We are pleased to announce this new article introducing Concurnas on <a href="https://www.programmez.com/actualites/concurnas-un-langage-pour-la-jvm-dedie-la-programmation-parallele-et-distribuee-30276">programmez.com!</a> - [French]</p></description></item>
<item><title>InfoWorld article on Concurnas</title><link>https://www.infoworld.com/article/3528755/concurnas-language-taps-jvm-for-high-performance-apps.html</link><description><p>We are pleased to announce this new article introducing Concurnas on <a href="https://www.infoworld.com/article/3528755/concurnas-language-taps-jvm-for-high-performance-apps.html">InfoWorld!</a></p></description></item>
<item><title>efinancialcareers article on Concurnas</title><link>https://news.efinancialcareers.com/uk-en/3003214/leave-algorithmic-trading-job</link><description><p>Ever wondered what Jason Tatton, the Founder of Concurnas, used to do before creating Concurnas? Find out in this article on <a href="https://news.efinancialcareers.com/uk-en/3003214/leave-algorithmic-trading-job">efinancialcareers</a></p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas is now part of the SDKMAN! platform</title><link>https://concurnas.com/download.html</link><description><p>We are proud to announce that Concurnas is now part of the <a href="https://sdkman.io/sdks#concurnas">SDKMAN! platform</a>. This greatly improves accessibility for Linux users. We also offer a direct Windows .msi installer. Both of these options make installation of Concurnas a breeze. <a href="https://concurnas.com/download.html">Download Concurnas today</a></p></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas 1.14.019 released</title><link>https://concurnas.com/download.html</link><description><a href="https://concurnas.com/download.html"> Download it...</a></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas 1.14.017 released</title><link>https://concurnas.com/download.html</link><description><a href="https://concurnas.com/download.html"> Download it...</a></description></item>
<item><title>Concurnas 1.14.016 released</title><link>https://concurnas.com/download.html</link><description><a href="https://concurnas.com/download.html"> Download it...</a></description></item>
<item><title>Getting started with Concurnas video</title><link>https://concurnas.com/video/index.html</link><description>Getting Started with Concurnas - covering the Concurnas REPL, concc and conc command line tools. <a href="https://concurnas.com/video/index.html"> Watch it...</a></description></item>
</channel>

</rss>